[laughing]
Up, up! Up, up!
[barking]
[laughing playfully]
Go get it!
Whoa!
[laughing]
-[dog growling]
-What is it, boy?
[growling and barking]
Hey!
I think you dropped your doll.
Well, hello there!
Hi, I'm Arin!
Ah, I wasn't supposed
to tell anyone my name.
Hmm, why not?
My, uh, teacher told me
not to tell strangers who I am,
ever.
Well, Arin, I'm Koji,
and that's Aru and Ume.
Hi!
So now we're not strangers.
[chuckling warmly]
How can we help you?
Well, I could use some food,
and maybe some water.
Of course,
I'm willing to work for it!
Anything around here
you need help with?
I know how to water plants,
fold laundry, make pies,
whatever...
[chuckling]
We can figure that out later.
First things first.
Join us for dinner.
[laughing] Yeah!
Thanks.
[dog barking]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja
for what's right ♪
[screaming]
[scream turns into laughter]
[laughing] Oh, wow,
that Lobbo guy
sounds like a laugh riot.
"Lobbo Lobbo!"
[laughing]
[sighing]
Thank you so much
for everything.
[Aru] Thanks.
Uh, I can't take this.
Please!
You need someone
to protect you out there.
Maybe I do.
Thanks again.
Come back anytime.
Lobbo Lobbo.
[laughing]
[sighing]
I'm back.
[growling]
[Ras] You were gone too long.
Did you bring food?
I did.
[grumbling] Mm...
Did you steal this?
Here it comes. Nrrr...
Here comes the bounty.
[Ras grunting] Mm-mm.
Nrr...oom!
Or have to
attack the villagers for it?
I just said the magic word.
You know incantations?
[chewing] Mm... mm...
I said "please."
Some people just want to help.
[chomping] Mm...
You can't depend on help.
If you want true power,
you need to take things
by force.
People always act
in their own self interest.
Put that away!
It's time to focus
on your training.
Get up.
[gulping] I--
[growling]
Of course.
Your form is sloppy.
Shoulders back.
Lower your center.
[grumbling]
[grunting with effort]
Whoa! [grunting]
Weeks of training,
and you're still not improving.
I thought I was.
I can see the doubt
on your face.
Push through your weakness.
Focus on your strength,
on your anger.
Turn your hurt into power.
But that's not how the Ninja--
The Ninja are no longer
your teachers!
[gasping and wheezing]
Ah... yes, there it is.
I need to know,
did you cause the Merge?
Yes...
[screaming]
Arin!
[screaming] No!
[screaming]
[gasping]
[Ras grumbling] Mm...
Never doubt my teachings.
[sniffing]
[whining sadly]
[sighing]
Riyu's lost Arin's scent.
Well, Arin
had to have come this way,
so let's keep on this path.
[sniffing]
[whining]
[Lloyd] Okay,
didn't see this coming.
Why didn't Arin leave
like a trail of pie crumbs
or something
so we could follow him?
Because I'm not sure
he wants to be followed.
[sniffing]
[whining]
You ask me,
the cave seems way more likely.
That other way is super rocky
and dangerous.
My thoughts as well,
but the cave is too small
for Zanth to enter.
I can take her
down the mountain
and search that direction
while you explore the cave.
I don't love the idea
of sending you
down that way alone.
[Zanth snorting]
[Zane] I will not be alone.
It is a good idea
to search both directions.
Just be careful.
"Careful"
would be my middle name
if Nindroid naming conventions
allowed for such things,
which they do not.
Good luck, Zane.
We'll meet you
on the other side.
Uh, that came out weird.
I mean, of the mountain,
not meet you
in the Departed Realm.
Does the Departed Realm
still exist after the Merge?
That's actually
a very good question,
but I'm hoping
we don't have to find out
anytime soon.
I can see the path ahead.
Follow me! I got this!
[quietly]
Who made this guy boss?
He's just trying to be helpful.
Ease up on him a little.
[Sora] What?
I haven't said
anything sarcastic all day.
[Frak] I've got a really great
cave sense.
[mocking] "I've got
a really great cave sense."
Okay, so one
sarcastic thing now.
[snorting chuckle]
Us Serpentine are brilliant
at underground spaces.
This is just like
the Ninjago sewers.
Well, except the smell's
a little, uh, different.
[candle tumbling]
[Sora gasping]
Not creepy at all.
Ah... check this out!
It's just like the stuff
I've been studying.
You study cave writing
in your spare time?
Sure.
I'm interested
in all things speleological.
No one has ever said that.
Okay,
well, I can't translate these
without my books,
but from what I can tell,
this cave has been used before.
Wow.
You learned all of that
from your spel... obian books?
[scoffing]
"Speleology," please.
Can we not bicker?
Let's go.
Look! There's--
-Another tunnel!
---another tunnel!
Let's go this way.
Uh, this looks tight.
If you're worried,
let me lead the way.
Hope no one is claustrophobic.
Huh, probably
should've asked that
before we started.
[grunting]
[gasping]
[Frak] Hey, you okay?
I'm fine.
There's a cool
Serpentine trick I use
when I start to get
claustrophobic.
I just breathe in
through my nose...
[inhaling]
...then hiss it out.
[exhaling, hissing]
[inhaling]
[shuddering exhale]
What now, cave man?
Let me just move
some of these rocks.
You sure those aren't, like,
holding up the cave roof
or something?
Speleologist here.
[stones rumbling]
But what's that sound?
I don't hear anything.
-[stones crumbling]
-It's a cave-in.
I shouldn't've moved
those rocks!
Run!
Uh, oh, but, yay, I was right!
There's a light up ahead!
[rocks crumbling]
We're saved!
We're not saved.
Any ideas?
I can't stop the cave-in
with my quake powers.
It's too big, too fast!
Riyu, can you--?
[screaming]
I'm bored.
This is boring!
B-O-R-ing.
I bet Lloyd and Sora and them
are having none of the borings.
[groaning]
You wanna blow up some rocks?
[groaning] Ugh.
You never have to ask
such things.
[♪♪♪]
[laughing]
[screeching]
Ooh!
It's for me, it's for me!
Ooh, I wonder who it's from.
Aw...
look at that.
Roby!
Go away!
Aw, cute.
He wants me to send a selfie!
[Kai] Photobomb!
Take this to Roby.
'Kay, thanks!
Wait.
Should I have waited
a few minutes
before sending that?
Am I gonna seem too needy?
Unsend! Unsend!
Will you two please focus?
Am I the only one that cares
about finding Jay?
[sighing] You're right, Nya.
I haven't been much help.
[scoffing] You really haven't.
It's just...
I don't know what to do,
and when I don't know
what to do,
I hit rocks with fire.
Hard relate.
[sighing]
I get it.
This whole thing
is overwhelming,
but we need to focus
and come up with a plan.
If we don't,
Jay could be lost forever.
[grunting]
Huh?
[groaning] Uh...
Oh, you're awake!
Here, this will help your arm.
[wincing]
...but not your nose.
My apologies.
[wincing]
[sighing] Thanks.
So... who are you?
Where am I?
What happened?
My name is Tyr,
head of the Dragonian tribe,
and you're in our village.
Some of us found you
in the river,
and I gotta admit,
they're a little disappointed
that you weren't a tasty fish.
Sorry for not being a fish.
But what about my friends?
[snoring]
They'll be fine
as soon as they wake.
But here, you must be hungry.
[slurping]
[♪♪♪]
[crowd bustling and laughing]
[Sora] Wow, these designs
are beautiful.
It's an old Oni design.
What's an Oni?
[sudden silence]
Did I say something wrong?
[gasping]
[quietly]
The Oni were this race
of super-evil demons
at war with the dragons
a long time ago, and--
-Why?
-Why what?
Why were they at war
with the dragons?
Because of...
evil reasons.
So you don't know?
The Oni and Dragons
were part of the First Realm,
and were at war
even before the First
Spinjitzu Master was born.
And he was like
a relative of yours, right?
Right.
He originally came from
the Realm of the Oni
and the dragons, too.
That's exactly
what I was gonna say.
The First Realm?
But where was that?
Looks like...
we're in it now.
This must be where
the First Realm appeared
during the Merge,
but only dragons
and these Dragonians
are left here now.
And they're on our side.
Man...
if I ever saw
one of those evil Oni...
[shuddering]
I wonder if anyone
has seen Arin.
Let's ask Tyr.
Actually,
you know who would know?
Them.
Old ladies know everything
that happens in a village.
Ooh, hi there, sweet pea,
what's good?
We're looking for my friend.
Have you seen him?
Maybe,
but we're going to need
more information
than "my friend."
We don't know your life.
Oh, yeah.
His name is Arin.
He's this high.
Is probably wearing a hood?
With horns on it!
Ooh, that guy!
Why didn't you say "horns"
first?
So you know where he is?
Yes!
Well, no.
We did.
But he looked kinda Oni-like,
what with the horns and all,
so we chased him away.
Right toward the South Woods.
He was alone?
Well, he wasn't
with anyone else
when we saw him,
but we don't know
his relationship status,
if that's what you're asking.
Well, the good news is
he's alive.
Yes!
Well, no.
He was.
But he's probably dead now.
Cyclops.
Cyclops...
Cyclops?
[together] Cyclops.
There've been cyclops sightings
from some other realm
in the South Woods.
Yup.
We sent
a Dragonian Hunting Party
out to look into it, but...
But...
But?
[together]
They never came back.
Okay...
Arin is a Ninja.
He could survive.
Yeah.
Even if there were a--
[together] Cyclops.
--that doesn't mean
Arin isn't still alive.
So, into the South Woods we go.
[forest birds calling]
[sniffing]
Got his scent, Riyu?
[grumbling affirmatively]
-Yes!
-Yeah!
[sniffing]
[growling]
Who else you smelling? Ras?
The Forbidden Five?
[all] Whoa...
What is this place?
It looks like someone's home.
Kinda cozy, actually.
[muffled cries]
You hear that?
It's coming from...
the ground?
[muffled voices crying out]
I think it's coming
from under that rock!
Give me a hand.
[grunting with effort]
Push with your knees,
not your back!
I know!
This isn't my first
giant rock, Frak!
[stone grinding]
It's the hunting party!
They're still alive!
Kinda!
Get us out of here!
[grunting]
Take my hand!
[heavy thudding]
I don't wanna turn around...
[footsteps thumping]
[roaring]
I am PowerLid!
The ultimate cyclops!
[roaring]
Also known as
the Ultimate Object
of Admiration!
[whispering] I don't think
that last part is true.
[PowerLid roaring]
Wait here
while we deal with this guy.
Ugh, would you?
He's super annoying.
[roaring]
H'yah!
He's annoying, but also strong.
Lloyd, your Spinjitzu!
Yeah, feels weird.
[PowerLid roaring]
Eat rocks, Ninjerks!
Ha!
Hit me all you want.
PowerLid can't feel a thing!
Stub my toe, no pain!
Bonk my head?
Nothing!
I can't even feel love.
But PowerLid is not ready
to expose himself emotionally.
[sniffling]
Eat more rocks!
Wait, don't move!
Cyclopses don't perceive depth
with just one eye.
He can't separate us
from our surroundings
as long as we don't move!
[stomping]
[sniffing]
Ninja?
Where you go?
Just kidding,
PowerLid can see you!
[gasping]
That's a stupid
and harmful Cyclops stereotype!
[stomping]
You little know-it-all!
You almost got us killed!
[panting]
[roaring]
[grunting with effort]
[yelping]
H'yah!
Nothing is working!
[grunting and gasping]
Run from PowerLid!
The Ultimate Object
of Admiration!
Is that all you got?
That rock was pretty heavy.
Denser than it looked, maybe.
Probably peridotite, or gabbro.
Just saying, it looked tiny...
for someone who calls himself
the Ultimate Object
of Admiration.
I can pick up bigger!
Watch! [roaring]
Ha!
Nice aim, Tiny Rocks.
[PowerLid grunting] H'yah!
[Sora] Nope! [laughing]
Stop moving, little Ninja!
Tell you what,
I'll stop moving
if you can pick up that rock
and throw it at me.
Promise?
That rock not that heavy, even!
Watch PowerLid.
PowerLid is swole!
[grunting]
[groaning]
PowerLid getting tired.
Maybe not enough protein today.
Doesn't count unless
you lift it over your head.
It count!
Nope!
[grunting]
[straining]
Ha!
[groaning]
Oof!
Yeah!
[laughing in triumph]
Quick thinking, Sora.
Nice.
Yeah.
Now let's get-- going?
Who are you?
What was that all about?
[grunting and snoring]
[murmuring sleepily]
Object of Admiration...
[snoring]
[♪♪♪]
Any chance you've seen
my friend, Arin?
He was wearing a hood
with horns, and--
Dragging someone on a sled?
Maybe?
When did you see him?
Was he okay?
Mm, no idea.
We were kinda busy
being stuck in a cyclops hole,
but I think he went that way.
Great!
He's headed South.
Come on--
What now?
Wanna serpent-splain
"South" to me?
No! I...
I want to apologize.
Oh.
I...
I know I could have
gotten us all killed.
I was trying to show you
I'm not just Ras's stooge.
We know that. Kinda.
Maybe I could've stopped Arin
from going with Ras
if I had just talked to him.
It's not your fault.
You really believe that?
Yeah,
because...
I think it's my fault.
Arin and I weren't talking
when he left.
He was my first friend.
Did you know that?
I... didn't.
Yeah, well,
I'm not very good at
making friends.
So, you two ready or what?
-Yes.
-Of course.
[Ras groaning and wheezing]
We should stop soon,
eat a bit,
maybe put on some sunscreen.
[wheezing]
No!
Keep moving!
You can't run from the sun.
It'll only take a minute.
[growling]
I demand we go faster!
You think
I don't want to find my parents
as fast as we can?
But we can't be stupid
out here.
I promised we'd find
your parents,
and I always keep my word!
[wheezing]
But my injuries are grave.
I must heal.
Of course.
To do that,
there's only one place
we must go...
The Spectral Lands.
[♪♪♪]